Abhijeet Lokhande, Data Scientist and ML Engineer

London, United Kingdom, abhijeetlokhande1996@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ablds/, https://github.com/abhijeetlokhande1996

PROFILE

Data Scientist and Machine Learning Engineer with proven experience in Natural Language Processing(NLP), Geo-spatial Data Science, Large Language Models(LLM), Deep Learning, Generative AI and Predictive Modelling. Proficient in location intelligence, Python, AWS, LangChain and Data Engineering. Winner of Built-AI ML Hackathon.

SKILLS

AWS, AWS S3, SQL, MongoDB, Apache Kafka, Time-Series Analysis, XGBoost, Machine Learning, Data Engineering, Deep Learning, Large Language Models(LLMs), Data Visualization, Generative AI, Geospatial Data Science and Analysis, NLP, Python, PyTorch, TensorFlow, Pandas, Scikit-Learn, Git, Docker, MLFlow, Django, FastAPI, Flask, Natural Language Processing(NLP), CI/CD, Angular, Javascript.

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

Built AI Apr 2020 - Present

Data Scientist London, UK

- Reduced rent per square foot error by 60% by improving the existing predictive machine learning model by developing a 3D cosine kernel and using the time dimension in the data. Implemented the Leave One Out strategy to evaluate the error.
- Improved link rate of London property databases by 30% by improving the existing linking algorithm by developing the NLP model to detect various components in the UK address and developing robust data preprocessing pipeline.
- Reduced project creation time on the Built AI platform from 55 mins to 30 mins by improving
 the existing NLP model by integrating AWS Textract and developing a custom integration
 algorithm.
- Reduced generation time of location intelligence maps by 40% by optimising the existing algorithm by integrating precomputed location grid references developed in GeoPandas.

King's College London

March 2021 - January 2022

Data Scientist London, UK

- Enhanced the novelty score of drug structure by 63% by developing a new Deep Learning model by using Graph Convolution Network and Generative Adversarial Network(GAN).
- Designed and implemented a robust data preprocessing pipeline for clinical data, ensuring accuracy and completeness of the million rows dataset.
- Improved the existing XGBoost model by performing feature engineering on the training data and using the Bayesian Optimization Technique to find the best hyperparameters for the classification model. As a result, the error rate was reduced by 20%.

Aspect Ratio

February 2018 - June 2020

Data Scientist Pune, India

- Developed web-based forecasting model for more than 100 countries to predict patient progression and revenue of a drug.
- Developed a dashboard of polished visualisations to share results of data analyses.
- Improved R2 score of regression model by 20% by improving existing machine learning model by implementing feature engineering.

EDUCATION

King's College London

September 2020 - June 2022

MSc in Data Science London, UK